快去安全舱
Quick! To the safe room!
别跑 再跑我开枪了
Run and you're dead!
- 我们只要人质 - 不要杀死他们
We want hostages, not dead bodies!
快开门 信不信我杀了你们
Open up or we'll kill you!
快点 我顶不住了
Hurry! I can't hold on much longer!
紧急呼叫
Mayday! mayday!
这里是中国商船广东号
This is Chinese merchant ship, Guangdong.
我们受到海盗袭击
We're under pirates attack! We're under pirates attack!
海盗上来了
They're coming up!
这是中国海军
This is the Chinese Navy.
请立刻停船
Stop the ship immediately!
这是中国海军
This is the Chinese Navy.
请立刻停船
Stop the ship immediately!
报告舰长
Captain.
蛟龙一队及二队
Jiaolong Unit One and Unit Two
已经成功潜入控制人质的地点
are near the hostage area.
蛟龙三队已经抵达机房区
Jiaolong Unit Three is in the engine room
在找可以把船弄停的方法
trying to stop the ship.
一号位置报告情况
Alpha position, report your situation.
报告
Reporting.
驾驶室有三名海盗控制着15名人质
There are 3 pirates and 15 hostages on the bridge.
二号位置什么情况？
Beta position, report your situation.
报告 食堂目标已锁定 完毕
Canteen target locked. Over.
报告舰长 所有油阀都被破坏了
Reporting. They disabled the fuel valves.
我们没办法截停船的供油
We can't turn off the fuel supply.
我现在去切断电路 把船停下
I'll cut the power and stop the ship.
报告舰长 政委
Captain, Commissar.
广东号突然再加速
They picked up the speed!
我们还剩多长时间？
How much time is left?
报告
Sir.
广东号现在以23节的速度继续前行
The ship is traveling at 23 knots.
如果以这个速度
At this speed,
15分钟后
we'll be in Somalian waters
进入索马里海域
in 15 minutes.
舰长
Captain.
我们绝不能进入他国领海
We must not enter territorial waters.
杨锐
RuiYang,
我们还剩十分钟就要撤离
you have ten minutes.
全体注意
Attention, everyone.
为保证所有人质安全
For the hostages' safety, attack as one.
各位置必须同步攻击 等我命令 完毕
Wait for the orders. Over.
左侧收到
Left flank, roger.
狙击点 狙击点
Sniper's hide.
收到 收到
Roget.
你们那边有没有把握？
Can you get a fix on them?
如果没有
If not,
我这边三分钟之后开始强攻
we'll start the attack in three minutes.
队长 队长
Captain.
两分钟之内给你回复 完毕
We'll report in two minutes. Over.
李懂
Dong Li.
我们这边有没有什么机会？
What's our opening like?
船头到船尾方向乱流很多
The ship is rolling, the direction is unsteady.
平均风速45到55之间
Headwinds at 45-55.
要避免气流对子弹的影响
For a reliable line of fire,
我们必须和驾驶舱保持120到150米之间
we need to be within 120 to 150 meters.
现在船速是23节
At 23 knots,
最佳的射击位置
we'll have an optimal position
开枪的时间只有三秒
for only three seconds,
否则船就会撞过来
or we have a risk of collision.
海鸟一号 有没有问题？
Seabird One, all clear?
没问题
All clear.
队长 队长
Captain.
十秒之内开始狙击
We'll attack in ten seconds.
完毕
Over.
全体准备
Standby.
进攻 进攻
Attack!
数据不变
There is no changes.
风向西北
Northwest wind.
风速20.8
The velocity is 20.8.
时间三秒
The time is three seconds.
数据稳定
Data steady.
稳定
Steady.
蹲下 全部蹲下 全部
Down! Everyone down!
报告舰长 人质全部安全
Captain, the hostages are safe,
但是驾驶室已无法控制货船 让船停下
but we can't stop the ship.
报告 如果船再不停下
Reporting. If the ship still doesn't stop,
五分钟后必须弃船
we'll have to abandon the ship in five minutes.
徐宏 报告你那边的情况
Hong Xu, report your situation.
他们守着发电机
They have the generator.
短时间内没办法拿下
We're running out of time.
现在唯一的办法是我强攻
We need to storm in
炸掉液压机 让船停下
and blow up the hydraulics.
如果船停不下
If the ship doesn't stop,
五分钟后所有人必须弃船
everyone must leave the ship in five minutes.
盾牌给我
Give me the shield!
你们两个守在这里
You two stay here.
石头
Shfiou,
跟我走
come with me!
上面 一个
Up there. One.
舰长 现在准备炸掉主轴液压装置
Ready to blow up the hydraulics!
队长
Captain,
发现枪杀船员的海盗上了小艇跑了
the hostage-taker is escaping on a boat!
队长
Captain!
我去追
I'll chase him.
不行 罗星
No, Xing Luo!
前方海域太多海盗
There are too many of them.
太危险了
It's too dangerous!
他们杀了人 不能让他们逃走
We can't let him go!
好吧
All right.
我批准你们的行动
Permission granted,
但是注意一点
but be careful.
不要跨过他国空域
Don't cross into territorial waters.
进入他国空域之前
I promise I'll get him
我一定会抓住他
before we cross into territorial waters.
蛟二全体 蛟二全体
Jiaolong Unit Two.
登船准备抓人
Board the ship and arrest them!
报告舰长 政委
Captain, Commissar.
三艘海盗快艇正在接近
Three pirate boats are approaching!
罗星
Xing Luo.
我们和海盗艇
We must maintain
必须保持300米的安全距离
a 300-meters safe distance.
海鸟一号 海鸟一号
Seabird One!
你们不能再追了
You can't go any further.
立即停下
Stop now!
海鸟一号收到
Roget.
请再给我一次机会
Give me one more chance!
把飞机拉横
Pull up the plane!
李懂
Dong Li.
你来解决那些支援
You should handle the others!
稳住 稳住
Steady!
海一 海二
Sea One and Two.
目标已经停下
The target has stopped.
你们上船抓人 我来掩护你们
Arrest them, I'll cover you!
海一 海二收到
Sea One and Two copy that!
我来
' got it!
罗星
Xing Luo!
队员中枪
Man down!
重复 队员中枪
Repeating. Man down!
谁呀？谁中枪了？
Who? Who was shot?
罗星
Xing Luo.
是罗星
It's Xing Luo.
报告舰长 政委
Captain, Commissar.
海一 海二已经成功捕获海盗
The pirates are in custody.
罗星已经脱离危险了
Xing Luo is safe.
现在情况稳定
His condition is stable.
但是
But
他必须要留在吉布提集中治疗
he has to stay in Djibouti to get treatment.
所以大家放心吧
Don't worry.
都回去休息
Get some rest.
舰长
Captain.
跟队员们都说了？
Have you told them?
说了
Yes.
就是…
Except that
他的脊柱神经被打穿
it pierced his spinal nerve.
我没说
I didn't tell them that.
老弟
Rm .
你听过…
Have you heard this?
"只解沙场为国死
A soldier should know about sacrifice.
何须马革裹尸还"吗？
And that he may never return.
他们都应该非常清楚军人的责任
They should understand the soldiers' duty.
其实你可以坦白的告诉他们真相
You can tell them the truth.
你是队长 不是家长
You're the captain, not their parent.
老是把队员们所有的包袱都往自己身上背
Don't take all of this personally
早晚得把你自己压死
or the stress will kill you.
压死也没办法
I can't help it.
责任确实是我的
It's my responsibility.
一星期后
我们的目标就是他
This is our target. William Parsons.
威廉·柏森
He is the head of development
他是伊维亚共和国
at an energy company in Yewaire.
一间能源公司的开发部主管
His department works on
他的部门负责开采铀的业务
the mining of uranium
还有在外地采购黄饼[核原料]的工作
and obtaining "yellow cake" in foreign countries.
怪不得我们一直想不通
That's why we couldn't figure out
黄饼的来源
where the "yellow cake" came from.
2014年10月
October, 2014.
他被调查的时间
The month he was investigated.
不就和那批没记名的黄饼
That was the same time
被偷运的时间一样？
the unmarked "yellow cake" was smuggled in.
就是嘛
Exactly.
线人说
My guy says
威廉手上仍有一批数量不少的黄饼
that William still has access to an abundant amount of "yellow cake".
他刚得到
And he has
制造脏弹[核污染炸弹]的技术
just acquired the technology to make 30 bombs.
现在伊维亚的局势这样紧张
The situation in Yewaire is tense.
如果那批黄饼仍在那里的话
If that "yellow cake" is still there,
他很有可能会尽快交易并把黄饼运走
he wants to finish the deal and get rid of it.
我们一定要跟着这条线
We must follow this lead.
关于威廉还有另外一个新闻
There is another report on William
有一个少女之前遭到性虐待
about a sexual abuse case of a young girl.
所有的证据都直指威廉
Okay? And all evidence points to him.
线人接触过她
My guy talked to the girl and she said
她提到威廉从来不会脱下脖子上的项链
William never took off his necklace
因为他说里面有一个
because he said it contains a secret
可以让世界大乱的秘密
that would turn the world into chaos.
我查到了
I've got it.
我马上就飞一趟
I'm going straight there.
但同时明天一早
And tomorrow morning,
我会让阿布出一整版的报料
Abu will publish a full-page report.
看看能不能延缓一下他们的行动
Let's do something to sabotage their plan.
这件事你别再跟进了
Don't take this any further.
你也知道
You already know
现在恐怖分子对你不利
the terrorists are onto you.
那又怎样？
So what?
现在不是刺你几刀的问题
It's not about scaring you,
也不是你个人怕不怕的问题
nor it is about you being scared.
Albert 你应该比谁都清楚
Albert, you know better than anyone
我为什么离开之前那几家大的报社
why I left those big newspapers.
不就是因为他们总是选择性的报导吗？
It's because they always do selective reporting
到最后总是掩盖事实真相
and covered up the truth!
- 而我记得你找我来 你跟我说过 - 不
- When you hired me, you said-- - No!
- 你需要一个敢于走近真相的人 - 不
- I have the guts to go expose the truth. - No!
- 所以我来了 - 不 不
- That's why I'm here! - No!
我欣赏你的拼劲
I appreciate your tenacity,
但是凡事总有一个限度
but there are limits.
你自己曾经坚持和相信的是不是已经忘了？
Did you forget what you stand for?
"如果你的照片不够好 那表示你还离得不够近"
我绝对不容许我再有员工有生命危险
I definitely won't risk the lives of my staff!
总有一些东西比生命更重要
But there are things that are more important than life.
今天凌晨3点43分
At 0300 hours this morning,
我舰接到外交部发来的紧急消息
the Foreign Ministry sent an urgent message.
就在五天前
Five days ago, there was a coup in Yewaire.
伊维亚共和国发生了军事政变
By order of the Central Military Commission,
根据中央军委命令
the Naval Command appoints us
海军指示我舰
to head to Yewaire immediately
即刻前往阿拉伯半岛的伊维亚共和国
and evacuate all Chinese citizens.
撤离我国在那儿的侨民
It has been five days since the civil war
伊维亚共和国发生内战
broke out in the Republic of lhwea.
已经五天
And the insurgence played by General Sharaf
由沙拉夫将军率领的叛军
have already seized the Republic's major cities.
已占领多个主要城市
Our footage shows that large
片段所见
groups of citizens and expats
大批市民和各国侨民纷纷逃离战区
are fleeing the war zone.
另有消息指出
In addition,
内战中有多人失踪或被绑架
sources claim that many people were missing
包括外国侨民
or abducted during the civil war
及伊维亚政府高层官员
including expats and high-level officials
怀疑是国内极端组织
of the lhwea government.
扎卡所为
And is is expected to be
这个扎卡
an act by the country's extremist group Zaka.
为了让伊维亚政府承认他们的组织
This group, Zaka, has been spreading terrorism
多次发动恐怖袭击
in the bid for recognition.
近两年
For the past two years,
更是联合了多个极端主义恐怖组织
they joined other extremist groups
在欧亚地区展开行动
across Europe and Asia and get into action.
这次伊维亚的军事政变
During this coup,
就是扎卡支持了
Zaka has supported
号称"疯子"的沙拉夫将军
General Sharaf who also known as Madman.
根据外交部提供的人员名单
According to the list given by the Foreign Ministry,
目前我们需要从伊维亚撤走的
we need to evacuate
我国登记人员130人
a total of 130 Chinese citizens
还有我国公司的外籍雇用人员30人
and 30 foreign staff of Chinese companies.
临沂号立即前往伊维亚执行任务
Linyi is to sail for Yewaire.
其余舰只返航
The other ships will return home.
- 你干嘛？- 对不起 对不起…
- What are you doing? - Sorry.
集合了
Let's go.
全体注意
Listen up!
这次任务的性质
For this mission,
要求我们只能以小分队作战
we'll break into small teams.
不能携带大量弹药
We can't carry much ammunition.
上级已经协调了当地的政府军
The local army
提供弹药支援
will supply materials.
但是他们的子弹口径和武器
But their weapons and calibers
都跟我们不同
are different from ours.
所以我们这一次也要改用
So we'll be using defensive weapons
欧盟的武器和装备
from the EU.
你动我糖啦？
Did you touch my candy?
原来调过来的是顾顺
So they've sent us Shun Gu.
听说他很拽的
I heard he's pretty arrogant.
果然闻名不如见面
See for yourself.
报告队长
Captain!
狙击手顾顺报到
Sniper Shun Gu is reporting.
欢迎
Welcome.
李懂
Dong Li!
到
Present!
过来
Come here.
他是代替罗星的人 你们认识一下
Meet Xing Luo's replacement.
我是观察员李懂
I'm the spotter, Dong Li.
我是顾顺
I'm Shun Gu.
队长
Captain.
上级有特别任务
We have a special mission.
需要咱们过去对接一下
They need us now.
好 那这样
Right.
你带他认识一下我们队员
You should introduce him to the rest.
是
Yes, sir!
你能跟着罗星
If you were Xing Luo's spotter,
说明你有两下子
you must know your stuff.
找个机会
I look forward
让我见识见识
to seeing that.
那也让我见识一下你的本事
The feeling is mutual.
以后有的是机会
You'll have your chance.
听着 等一会政府军来
Listen, when the troop comes to
撤走威廉博士他们的时候
take Dr. William and the others,
我去拦车 你处理剩下的事
I'll stop them and you will take care of the rest.
明白了吗？
You got it?
你明白了吗？
明白 明白 放松点吧
Yeah, yes. I got it. Relax.
威廉博士 不要再催我了
Stop pushing me, Doctor.
你看看新闻
Look at the news.
到处都是军人
The military is everywhere.
现在可是一触即发
And the chaos, it is everywhere.
我不要听借口
I'm not in the mood to hear any excuses.
钱收了
You took the money,
事就得办
now the job is to have it done.
你答应我一星期
You promised me one week.
货必须运走
So the shipment must be on the plane.
否则有麻烦不只是我一个人…
If it's not, I'm not the only one who's going to be in trouble.
你是将军
You are the General.
我相信这难不倒你
And I'm sure that you can handle this situation.
何领事 第三批侨民车队
Consul He,the third group
已经顺利到达港口
has reached the port.
卢医生
Dr. Lu.
何领事
Consul He.
你好 你好
Hello.
夫人呢？
Where's your wife?
她公司稍后也会让她撤离的
Her company is doing the evacuation.
她那边情况到底怎么样？
How is it going over there?
别提了
You can't even imagine.
我这一出门太着急了
I rushed here in panic,
手机不知道落哪儿了
I don't even know where my phone is.
马上打给她
Call her now.
谢谢
Thank you.
喂？
Hello?
小梅吗？
-Mei?
你怎么一直不接电话？
Why didn't you pick up?
急死我了
I was so worried!
不用担心 我们已经到达领事馆了
Don't worry, we're at the consulate.
你那儿怎么样？
How is it over there?
轩轩和你都到了吗？
Are you there with Xian-xuan?
都到了 放心吧
Yes, don't worry.
我问问情况
- Let me talk to her. - Make sure Xian-xuan is with you.
何领事找你
Consul He wants a word.
邓梅啊？
Mei Deng?
我是何清流
It's Qing-liu He.
你那边怎么安排的？
What's your plan over there?
何领事您好
Hello, Consul He.
政府军会来公司接我们去一个临时安置点
Government troops are coming
再统一安排撤离
to coordinate
你注意啊
our evacuation.
要随时保持联系
Remember to keep in touch.
我知道
I know.
政府军一到 我马上通知你们
I'll call as soon as the troops arrive.
这不是你我能控制的
The situation could change so fast, and that's not under my control or yours.
是的
Yes,
我正在动用一切资源来解决这件事
I'm using all of my resources to settle this issue.
您必须相信我
You have to trust me.
报告舰长 政委
Captain, Commissar.
伊维亚批准我们进入奥哈法港口
We have permission to enter the port!
- 全舰进入二级战斗部署 - 是
- Battle-ready deployment grade two! - Yes, sir!
我们的舰来了
That's our warship!
来了 来了
It's here!
舰长
Captain.
伊维亚情况有变
We have a new situation in Yewaire.
他的总统今早遇袭重伤
There is an assassination attempt on the President.
现在由他的秘书长莫哈迪代理国务
The Chief Secretary Mohadi has taken charge for now.
伊维亚政府已向我外交部发出请求
Their government is asking us
希望我们能保护他的家人离开这里
to take his family to safety.
上级已经同意
Our superior has agreed
并指示我舰负责
and given Linyi this duty.
明白了
Understood.
我去调整一下安保
I'll check the security.
领事
Consul
人已经齐了
We've got everyone.
军方的车呢？
- How about the escort? - They're here.
车也到了
We'll leave straight away.
我们马上出发
- Go tell them! - Okay.
- 快去通知 - 好
Get your bags quickly.
大家赶紧收拾行李
We're leaving now!
准备出发了 快
Quick!
中国领事离开了 中国领事离开了
The Chinese consul has left.
走 把他们逼入战区
Let's go! Let's force them into the war zone!
阿布 蹲下
Hey, get down.
该死 是扎卡的人
Shit, it's Zaka.
扎卡的人闯进来了
Zaka is coming!
他们已经杀了警卫
They've killed the guards!
快逃 躲起来
Run! Hide yourselves!
冲过去 冲过去
Just push through!
通知后面的政府军车上前开路
Inform the army vehicle at the back to overtake
让侨民的车到我们前面来
and let the consul's vehicle follow their back.
中国领事车队刚刚转入战区
The convoy is in the war zone.
退 快退
Reverse! Quick!
快 倒车
Hurry, reverse!
后方有武装分子
There are rebels behind us.
马上联系军舰
Contact the warship now!
建立防守线
Set up a defensive line!
不要下车 趴下
Stay there, get down!
不能被困在这儿
Don't let them trap us!
我们躲进去 快
We need to hide, quick!
全部人立即下车
Everyone, get down from the car now!
快
Hurry!
跟上 一个一个来
Don't panic, one at a time!
快
Hurry!
快 快快快
Quick, quick!
你带领事走
Take the consul!
领事 快走
Consul, hurry!
中国侨民及领事躲在工厂里
The consul and others went into a factory.
舰长
Captain.
报告 我是杨锐
Rui Yang speaking.
刚刚接到驻伊领事何清流的求救电话
Consul Qing-liu He just sent an SOS.
他跟最后一批侨民在撤离途中遇到袭击
His convoy was ambushed.
伊维亚政府暂时无法提供人员营救
Yewaire can't spare any troops,
但是他们已经允许我们的部队进城救人
but we have their permission to go in.
并在港口提供交通支持
They'll clear the roads out of the port.
全体注意 全体注意
Listen up, everyone.
目标工厂所处街道目前我们无法进入
We can't get to the factory by road,
我们改由毗邻的居民楼屋顶进入工厂
so we'll go over the roofs.
那么一队
Unit One,
顾顺 李懂
Shun Gu, Dong Li.
你们负责留在厂外建立制高点
Your duty is to establish an over watch.
其余人跟我进工厂内搜救
The rest are on search and rescue.
二队 你们派三个人支援工厂外武警
Unit Two, send three people to help the military police.
其余五人留守车队
The rest will guard the convoy.
完毕
Over.
什么？第五大道也失守了？
What? We lost the Fifth Road?
不行…不能走拉法叶大道
No, don't go by Lafayette.
那里出路太少 去兹玛路拐过去吧
There are no escape routes. Try Zima Road.
别过来
Don't come.
找到威廉博士没有？
Did you find Dr. William?
还没找到
Not yet.
一定要把他找出来 他对我们很重要
Find him! He's the key.
快走 快走
Move it!
距离目标还有一分钟 全体准备
One minute before our target. Grab your guns!
支援武警
Support the military police.
我方人员受到袭击 请求还击
We are under fire. Permission to return fire!
同意
Granted.
零一零一 车队到达
Base, we've arrived at the target.
二队 留守车队
Unit Two, defend the convoy!
烟雾弹掩护
Smoke bomb!
左右两侧 建立防守线 快
Flanks, set up a defensive line!
零一零一 进入天台
Base, we're on the roof.
安全
All clear.
顾顺 李懂 找制高点
Shun Gu, Dong Li, find an over watch.
接近制高点
Approaching over watch.
零一零一 到达工厂天台
Base, we're on the factory roof.
一队进入
Unit One is in!
你停车 你的小孩就死定了
If you stop, the kids will die!
一定要撞过去
Crash into them!
否则我会一枪把他们脑袋轰掉
Or I'll blow their brains out!
你以为我在开玩笑？
Do you think I'm kidding?
是不是以为我在开玩笑？
See this?
看见没有 你停车 我就杀死他们
If you stop, they will be dead.
冲过去 给我炸死他们
Go on, blow them up!
我明白了
I understand!
狙击手就位
Sniper in position.
汽车炸弹 快把它截住
It's a car bomb! Stop it!
全部人躲开 全部人躲开
Everyone, take cover!
外面爆炸声 什么情况？
What was that explosion?
有汽车炸弹袭击关卡
There is a car bomb at the checkpoint.
政府军伤亡惨重
Heavy casualties for government troops.
二队 加强防守
Unit Two, step it up!
保住撤退点
Hold the evacuation point!
怎么了？有药吗？
What's wrong? Do you need the inhaler?
赶快 赶快
Hurry up!
我已经开到最快了
This is the fastest I can go.
分散守住所有出口
Block all exits!
把中国人都找出来
Find those Chinese people!
击毙 上
Got them. Move!
谁？
Who's there?
中国武警
Chinese military police!
- 陆琛 检查他 - 是
- Chen Lu, check his wounds. - Yes, sir!
中国海军
Chinese Navy.
我们带你们回家
We'll take you home.
- 安子 安子 收到吗？- 收到 请讲
An-zi, can you hear me?
我是领事何清流
- I'm Consul Qing-liu He. - Yes, I'm here.
你们在哪里？
Where are you?
我们被困了 在车间里
We are trapped in the workshop!
徐宏 庄羽 张天德
Hong Xu, Yu Zhuang, Tian-de Zhang.
你们带侨民撤离
Evacuate the citizens.
其他人跟我行动
Everyone else, come with me.
手雷
Grenade!
两个右边房间 一个在外面
There are two in the room and one is outside!
佟莉 压着他们打
Li Tong! Let them taste hell!
倒了一个
One down!
小心 火箭炮
Watch out! Bazooka!
撤
Move!
坚持住
Hold on!
庄羽 撤 撤
Yu Zhuang, move out!
走
Go!
石头
Shitou!
来 走
Come on, go!
撤退点 撤退点 侨民现在撤出
Evacuation point! We're on the way!
你们准备接应
Be ready!
全体掩护射击
Everyone, covering fire!
一队快速通过
Unit One is going through!
走 快点 快 蹲低一点
Quick, stay low!
注意
Watch out,
十二点方向怀疑是汽车炸弹
it is suspected that there is a car bomb at 12 o'clock!
快 上车 大家上车 快
Quick, get in!
一队 快走快走 有汽车炸弹
Unit One! Hurry! There is a car bomb!
把车截住
Stop the car!
救命呀 不要杀我
Don't kill me! Don't shoot!
我不是他们的人 他们逼我的
I'm not with them! They forced me!
他不是扎卡的人 把枪放下
He's not with Zaka! Lower your weapons!
怎么了？
What's wrong?
那些恐怖分子在平民身上装炸弹
Those terrorists. They've been bombing civilians.
让我来
I'll handle it.
叫你的人别动
Tell your men to stay calm.
石头 你替我位置
Shitou! Take my position.
狙击点 狙击点
Sniper's hide.
收到
I read you.
掩护我 我去那辆车
Cover me. I'm going to that car.
好
Roger.
冷静
Relax,
躺下
Get down.
不要杀我
Don't kill me!
放松
Relax,
没事的 没事的…
it's okay. It's okay.
没事的…
It's okay...
放松…
Relax,
别动
Don't move.
我的孩子 拜托
American, please.
救救我的孩子…
Save my kid.
我的孩子 拜托…
My kid, please.
走吧
Let's go.
拜托…
Please.
我们准备出来了
We're coming out!
张天德 撤
Tian-de Zhang, move out!
撤 撤 撤
Quick, move out!
狙击点 撤 狙击点 撤
Sniper's hide! Move out!
收到 撤
Roger! Moving out!
阿布 你怎么样？
Abu, are you okay?
我没事 你先去拿他的项链
I will get his necklace first.
刚刚收到外交部的消息
We just received news from The Foreign Ministry.
一个叫夏楠的记者
A French-Chinese reporter
是个法籍华人
called Nan Xia
联络了外交部12308热线
contacted their 12308 hotline.
这位记者表示 她看到了扎卡组织
She said she saw Zaka
绑架了一批能源公司的员工
kidnapping the staff of an energy company,
其中有一个中国公民叫邓梅
including a Chinese citizen, Mei Deng.
可信度高吗？
Is that reliable info?
我们已经与夏楠取得了联系
We made contact with Nan Xia
确认了她的身份
and confirmed her identity.
上级还在与伊维亚政府协调
The Yewaire government will help.
派出他们的直升机和支援部队
They'll supply ground and air support
一起执行营救
for the joint rescue mission.
我们这次行动的决心
Our mission this time
就是要让恐怖组织知道
is to give a message to all terrorists
一个中国人都不能伤害
that you can never harm a Chinese citizen.
二队
Unit Two,
把侨民先送回港口
take the citizens to the port.
一队
Unit One,
政府军会带你们到
go with their government troops
附近的集合点等待消息
and wait for orders.
装备 补给品还有空降服
We'll send in the materials, supplies,
会送到你们那里
and wing suits.
是
Yes, sir!
刚才他求我救他孩子的时候
When he asked me to save his kids,
我心里很难受
I felt awful.
人救了
We saved their lives,
可是家没了
but not their homes.
他们这个国家
This country of theirs
已经乱成这样了
is in such a mess.
我们顶多就是把任务完成
At most, we complete our mission
别的什么也做不了
and that's it.
你为什么总爱吃糖？
Why do you like candy so much?
看你认识我这么多年 不知道吧？
You still don't know after all this time?
我小时候特别调皮
I was a naughty kid.
总被妈妈打
I always got spanked.
打我一次呢
But each time,
就给我一块糖吃
my mom gave me a candy.
所以说到现在
So even now,
一出任务
when I'm on a mission,
只要有糖吃
if I have candy,
什么事儿都没了
I can handle anything.
打我干嘛？
What was that for?
不是说吃糖…
Didn't you say
不是说吃糖不疼吗？
if you have candy, there is no pain?
你知不知道我跟罗星有一场比赛要打？
Do you know Xing Luo and I were rivals?
知道
Yes.
你们要争委内瑞拉特种兵学校
You guys were fighting for a spot in a sniper training camp
狙击手训练营的入学资格
at a commando school in Venezuela.
全蛟龙只有一个名额
There's only one spot for Jiaolong.
可惜
It's a pity.
没机会跟他比一场
There is no chance to compete now.
他是我见过最好的狙击手
He was the best sniper I ever saw.
你以前也这样吗？
Were you always like this?
哪样？
Like what?
紧张
Tense.
抗压能力太差
Shaky under pressure.
战场上
On the battlefield,
子弹躲不掉的
you can't dodge bullets.
这一课
Take this
算哥送给你的
as a free lesson for you.
下次记得交学费
Next time, I'll ask for fees.
舰长 上级消息
Captain, we received news.
伊维亚政府军安排不了直升机
Yewaire can't spare any choppers.
他们只能让我们蛟龙队
We'll have to escort the convoy
跟随护送平民的车队
of civilian evacuees by road.
坐车去
If we go by road,
路上得多花费一倍的时间
it'll take twice as long.
我就是担心他们赶不回来
I worry they won't get back in time.
接蛟龙一队
Get me Jiaolong Unit One.
是
Yes, sir!
夏楠的手机信号
Nan Xia's phone
在伊维亚东北部地区消失了
was last found in the Northeast.
根据伊维亚政府提供的信息
According to the Yewaire authorities,
那里是一个叫巴塞姆的小镇
there's a town there called Basem.
一周前被扎卡组织占领
Zaka took over it
现在你们先去70公里外的
a week ago.
临时政府军集合点
Go to the Yewaire Army Meeting Point.
跟随护送平民的车队上路
Follow the evacuation convoy.
他们的特种部队会配合你们
Their commandos will work with you
一起营救邓梅
to rescue Mei Deng.
是
Roget
确定行动
The operation is confirmed.
但是我们只有三个小时时间
But we only have three hours.
我们这次会深入敌人的后方
We'll be deep in enemy territory.
但是到目前为止
But we don't have
我们还没有拿到一个准确的情报
any reliable intel until now.
我可以肯定地告诉大家
Only one thing is certain.
一场硬仗
It will be a tough battle.
所以我要求你们每一个人
I want each of you
打起精神来
to give it your all
平安回家
and return safely.
听明白了吗？
Do you understand?
明白
Yes, sir!
出发
Move now!
Sayyid
Sayyid.
秘书长夫人到港口了
The Chief Secretary's wife is at the port.
我会用那个中国女人质给他们压力
The Chinese hostage is our bargaining chip.
但他们不会轻易顺从
But they won't give in easily.
你留在这里 留意着她们的一举一动
Stay there and observe everything.
山上出现三辆皮卡车
There are three trucks on the hill.
其中有两辆武装了
Two are armed.
另外一辆被货厢盖住看不到
I'm not sure about the third.
什么时候出现的？
When did they appear?
三分钟前
Three minutes ago.
副炮进入战备状态
Prepare the auxiliary gun.
是
Yes, sir!
谢谢
Thank you.
我明白 但是我必须要去巴塞姆镇
I understand. But I have to go to Basem.
因为我除了要救我的助手以外
It's not just to save my assistant.
我还有一件非常重要的事情
There's something very important
我必须去那里完成
I have to do there.
对不起 夏小姐
I'm sorry, Ms. Xia.
我们不可能带着你去执行任务
We can't take you with us.
而且我们也不知道那边到底什么情况
We don't know the situation there.
对吧？
Right?
杨队长
Captain Yang,
你能让我把情况说明你再做决定吗？
can you let me explain first?
好
Okay.
徐宏 徐宏
Hong Xu,
赶紧催一下他们出发 快一点
get them moving. Quick.
我其实一直在追查黑市核原料黄饼的买卖
It's about the black-market "yellow cake".
被恐怖分子抓走的那个威廉
Zaka has William Parsons,
是其中最大的卖家
the biggest dealer in the market.
最近我们发现
We found out
他跟一些恐怖组织接触密切
that he's in touch with terrorist groups.
其中一个组织
One of them
已经拥有提高黄饼放射量的技术
now has the technology
用来制造能大规模传播污染物质的炸弹
for large-scale dirty bombs.
也就是说
Which means
黄饼一旦落到他们的手里
once they get the "yellow cake",
下一次恐怖袭击会死多少人
who knows how many
我们无法预估
they will kill?
你说的组织是扎卡 对吗？
Are you talking about Zaka?
扎卡只是想要抢走威廉手上的黄饼
Yes, all they want is the "yellow cake".
- 我们不管那是什么组织 - 而我是希望你们能把阿布
- It's not our business. - I hope you can save Abu,
- 把威廉 把所有的人都救出来 - 上级给到我们的任务就是…
- Our mission-- - William and all of them!
夏小姐 我们要执行的任务
Ms. Xia, our mission
就是要去解救一个中国公民
is to rescue a Chinese hostage.
如果尽可能的情况下
If we can,
我们会去救更多的人
we'll rescue the others.
但是对不起
But I'm sorry,
你不可以跟我们参与这次行动
you can't come with us.
如果我不跟你们去
If I don't go with you,
我没有办法拿到我要的东西
I'll never get what I came for!
请你上车
Please get in the car.
对不起 你不能离开
Sorry, you can't leave.
我为什么不能离开？
Why not?
我刚刚跟你讲过很多遍了
I already told you.
上级给我们的指示
We were ordered
是要把你安全护送到政府军沿途的基地
to take you to an army base.
再由政府军统一安排你们执行撤离
You'll be evacuated from there.
首长您好 我是夏楠
Sir, this is Nan Xia.
- 我想向您汇报一个情况 - 夏小姐…
- We have a situation. - Ms. Xia.
因为下一次恐怖袭击不知道会怎么样
In the next terrorist attack,
会死多少人
countless people will die
而且威廉现在有太多的黄饼在他…
because of William's "yellow cake".
怎么了？
What is it?
扎卡给政府军发了一段视频
Zaka put out a video
标明是给中国海军的
addressed to the Chinese Navy.
你看一下
Look.
秘书长莫哈迪罪孽深重
Chief Secretary Muhadi is a sinner
迫害自由的我族人民
who continues to suppress my people
滥用武力
with his abuse of violence.
我们强烈要求你们停止包庇罪人
We demand that you stop harboring
马上交出莫哈迪的家人
the sinner and turn over Muhadi's family.
我们必须为遭受莫哈迪迫害
We must avenge the brothers and sisters
而牺牲的兄弟姐妹报仇
who sacrificed because of Muhad.
否则
If you refuse to cooperate,
中国公民将代替他们接受惩罚
the Chinese citizens shall take the punishment in their place.
我现在就给你们一个示范
This is just an example.
下一个就是这中国女人
And this Chinese woman will be next.
他妈的
Damn it!
太嚣张了
Savages!
我们现在唯一的希望
Our only hope
就是蛟龙能顺利地把人质救出来
is for Jiaolong to rescue them all.
杨队长
Captain Yang.
是
Yes?
收到消息 前方可能有危险
We just got word about possible danger ahead.
我们需要改道了
We have to look for a different route.
什么？
What?
庄羽 联系军舰
Yu Zhuang, contact the base.
是
Okay!
快
Hurry!
零一零一 一队报告
Base, this is Unit One.
是否收到？
Do you read me?
零一零一 我是一队
Base, this is Unit One.
请求通讯 是否收到？
Request for signal. Over.
零一零一…
Base.
迫击炮
Mortar attack!
大家有没有事？
Is everyone okay?
快点回话 快点回话
Answer me!
我没事
I'm okay!
陆琛没事
Chen Lu's okay!
徐宏这边没事
Hong Xu's okay!
顾顺 李懂没事
Shun Gu, Dong Li, okay!
张天德 佟莉没事
Tian-de Zhang and Li Tong, okay!
待在这别动
Don't move!
石头 防守后方
Shitou, go to the rear!
佟莉 侧翼突击
Li Tong, take the wing!
等什么？把枪检起来
Come on! Get your gun!
陆琛 把敌人的阵地给我定位出来
Chen Lu, get me the enemy's position!
徐宏 去把人都带出来
Hong Xu, bring everyone out!
庄羽 看一下还有什么装备能用
Yu Zhuang, look for any ammunition that is left!
收到
Roger
开门
Open the door!
迫击炮在车队两点方向
Mortars at two o'clock!
快躲开 快躲开
Hide!
徐宏
Hong Xu!
没事
I'm okay.
救人
Save them!
快
Hurry!
陆琛 救人
Chen Lu, let's go!
顾顺 李懂
Shun Gu, Dong Li.
快找制高点 听我指示
Find an over watch, wait for my orders!
收到
Roger
张天德 掩护我
Tian-de Zhang, cover me!
走
Move!
佟莉 佟莉 掩护我
Li Tong, cover me!
李懂 上
Dong Li, move!
他的腿已经断了
His leg's gone,
拿刀把剩下的皮割断
let's cut it off!
来
Come on!
抬走
Take him.
冷静点
Stay calm.
队长 队长 我是徐宏
Captain, it's Hong Xu.
巴士其中一个炮弹已经启动了
There's a live bomb on the bus.
顾顺 就位没有？
Shun Gu, are you in position?
还没有
Not yet.
最后一发
Last round!
大家注意 有狙击手
Watch out! There is a sniper!
所有人小心
Be careful, everyone!
李懂 听我说
Dong Li.
我来解决敌方迫击炮阵地
Listen to me.
但是我一开枪
I'll hit their base.
对方狙击手一定会锁定我的位置
But as soon as I fire,
你尽快把他找出来
they'll have a fix on my position.
收到回复
Find them quickly.
收到
Do you read me?
顾顺 快
Roger
烟散了
Shun Gu, quick!
顾顺就位
The smoke is clearing up!
狙击手在你们的两点方向
Shun Gu in position.
车队旁边山头 靠近山顶的位置
There is a sniper at 2 o'clock,
有一块外露的大山石
on the hill, near the peak,
往东22度 距离是602米
by a boulder.
李懂 李懂
It's 22 degrees east, 602 meters.
看到他没有？看到他没有？
Dong Li. Can you see him?
看到 看到了
I see him.
最高处山脊线 往右十米
On the highest ridge,
ten meters to the right.
李懂 把他牵制住
Dong Li, pin him down.
我来解决迫击炮
I'll get the mortar.
顾顺 我牵制住他了
Shun Gu, I've pinned him down.
所有人撤退 所有人撤退
Everyone, retreat!
别动 别动
Don't move! Don't move!
你按着他 我来拔
Hold him down, I'll pull it out.
好
Okay.
拔
Pull!
按住他
Hold him down.
下去了
Let's go.
快走
Hurry!
所有人快走
Everyone, go now!
车里的炮弹快炸了
The bomb is going off!
快跑
Run!
徐宏 快走
Hong Xu, run!
队长
Captain.
队长 怎么样？
Captain, are you okay?
队长
Captain!
人呢？
Where are the others?
- 有没有事？- 快救人
- Are you okay? - Hurry and save the others!
出来
Come on!
石头
Shitou!
- 徐宏… - 救人
- Hong Xu... - Save the others!
徐宏 徐宏…
Hong Xu...
使劲拉
Harder!
拉
Pull!
快
Hurry!
夏楠
Nan Xia!
- 夏楠 - 在这里
- Nan Xia! - Over here!
使劲
Pull!
Harder!
有没有事？怎么样？怎么样？
Are you okay?
我们距离目的地还有80公里
We're 80 kilometers from our target.
但是军舰离港的时间只剩下一个半小时
But the ship sails in 90 minutes.
我们只有一辆狐式装甲可以用
We only have one vehicle left
还正在抢修当中
and that's under repair.
我们可能赶不回去了
We won't make it back in time.
他们政府军有没有其他的办法来保障我们？
Can their troops give us more support?
上级已经向伊维亚政府提出了要求
Our superiors put in a request,
但是对方表示现在还不能调动增援
but they've no troops to spare.
只能提供他们的一个支援点
They can only get us out at a point
在离目标以北60公里的地方
60 kilometers north of the target.
你们营救成功后
After the rescue,
可以先撤到那里
go straight there.
但是支援点和目标之间是一段高危地带
But it's a very dangerous route.
撤离的时候必须要小心
You need to be on high alert.
是
Roger that!
另外 扎卡发了一段视频
Also, Zaka released a video.
他们把那个记者助理的头给砍了
They beheaded the reporter's assistant.
我做过这么多演习
Despite all those drills
训练
and training,
没想过遇到这种情况
l never thought
完全控制不了自己
I'd lose control like that.
副队
Sir.
我没资格当蛟龙
I'm not good enough for Jiaolong.
你还记得我们是怎么成为蛟龙的吗？
Do you remember how we became a team?
我们经历过多少困难
We went through tough times.
想过多少次放弃
We were all tempted to quit,
可还是坚持下来了 对吧？
but we held on, right?
能站在这儿
The fact that we are here now
就说明我们每一个人都是合格的
proves we are all qualified.
想想我们的口号
Think of our motto.
"强者无敌"
"Conquer fear, conquer all."
刚刚表现很好
You did well just now.
我不是表现给你看的
It wasn't for show.
我看到了
Well, I saw it.
还疼吗？
Does it hurt?
有一点儿
A little.
别想多了
Don't think too much.
你可以跟我们一起去巴塞姆镇
You can come to Basem with us.
有支援了是吗？什么时候到？
Are we getting reinforcements? When?
我要跟你讲的是
Listen.
既然跟我们一起走
If you come with us,
请你服从我们的命令 好吗？
you have to follow orders, okay?
杨队长 我提醒你
Captain, let me tell you.
如果你的支援不到的话
Without reinforcements,
你不要轻易走
you have to be really careful.
因为这个路程一个多小时
It's more than an hour away.
你们的车能修好吗？
Can you fix the vehicle?
车 我们正在全力的抢修
We're doing our best.
这个东西不用你来操心
That's none of your concern.
我要跟你讲的是命令的问题
I'm talking about the orders.
就是
It's about
刚才的战斗
the battle just now.
我跟你强调了原地别动
I told you to stay put.
是 我理解你是为了救人 对吧？
Sure, it was to save a life.
但是我希望的是在下面的行动当中
But when there is action next time,
因为情况非常危险
considering the danger,
所以无论发生什么样的情况
no matter what happens,
请你能够百分之百的服从我们的命令
you do exactly as we say.
- 好… - 如果你的命令下错呢？
- Okay? - What if the order is wrong?
你怎么能保证你下的命令是对的？
How do you know it's right?
对 我们的身份是不一样
Yes, we have different roles,
但是我们的信念未必…
but as for our beliefs--
如果我的命令下错了 我自己负责
If I'm wrong, I take responsibility!
但如果你不服从命令 你死了
But if you disobey and you die,
请问谁来负责？
who will be responsible then?
如果的话…
If that's the case,
千万别救我
then don't save me.
报告队长 车好了 马上到
Captain, the vehicle has been fixed. Will be right there.
收到 收到
Roget
全体出发
Everyone, move now.
Sayyid 威廉现在情况怎样？
Sayyid, how is Dr. William?
人没事 不过还没醒来
He is alive. But still unconscious.
除了黄饼
Besides the "yellow cake",
一定要问出脏弹技术在哪里
we need the formula for the dirty bomb.
明白吗？
Understand?
明白 先生
Yes.
庄羽 庄羽
Yu Zhuang.
找一处高地
Find a high place.
架上卫星天线
Set up an antenna.
保持和舰上的联系
Keep contact with base.
收到
Roger that.
测试 测试
Testing, testing.
不要害怕
Don't be scared.
他们是中国军人 是来救人的
The Chinese Navy is here to rescue people.
不要害怕
Don't be scared.
这个屋子的主人贝拉说
The house owner, Bella,
一个星期前这里就被恐怖分子占领了
says they came a week ago,
把所有的男人都杀了
killed all the men,
把妇女和孩子都赶走
chased off the others,
只留下她们几个给他们做饭
and kept them hereto cook.
现在镇子上
In the town now,
恐怖分子大概有150个人左右
there are about 150 terrorists.
主要集中在广场附近活动
They stay around the square.
她画了一张图
She drew a map.
这是恐怖分子的指挥中心 在这儿
This is their headquarters.
这个广场北边 就是人质营
The hostage camp is to the north.
十几个人把守
They have about ten guards
里面现在有25个人质
and 25 hostages in there.
除了五个政府军以外
They are all foreigners
其他全部是外籍
except for five soldiers.
三个女性只有一个是亚洲女性
There are three women, one of them is Asian.
按她的描述应该就是邓梅
Her description matches Mei Deng's.
等一下
Hold on.
有多少条路通往这个人质营？
How can we access the camp?
只有广场一条
Only through the square.
先把我们这个情况跟舰上汇报一下
Send a situation report to the ship.
是
Yes, sir.
8对150
It's eight against 150 people.
你们以前有过这样的经验吗？
Have you ever done anything like this before?
我们这八个人的任务
Our unit's mission
不是要解决那150个人
is not to deal with those 150 people.
而是去营救那个必须去营救的中国人质
It's to rescue the Chinese hostage.
就是说其他的人还是没有希望了
So is there no hope for the others?
没时间了
There's no time.
那…有没有可能
Is it possible
如果你们可以的话
for you
再多救一个人？
to save one more person?
有没有这种可能？
Is there any chance of that?
你的助手阿布
Your assistant, Abu
已经被他们处决了
has been executed.
什么时候的事？
When did that happened?
我们来之前
Before we got here.
我的先生和我的孩子
My husband and child
也是死在像今天这样的大巴上
died on a bus just like today.
在零五年…
In 2005,
零五年伦敦炸弹袭击的时候
when they blew up the bus in London.
警察找到我跟我说
The police told me
什么都没有剩下
that nothing was left of them,
只有一个小小的蓝色的手链
but a little blue bracelet.
从那以后
That's when
我就要跟他们干到底
I vowed to fight against them to the end.
我要跟恐怖组织干到底
To fight against the terrorist groups.
我什么都不怕
I'm not afraid of anything,
我连死都不怕
even death.
我就是怕像今天这样没有办法
I'm only afraid of being powerless to help.
其实我谁都保护不了
I've failed to protect anyone.
其实我连阿布都保护不了
Not even Abu. I've failed to protect him.
我谁都…
I've failed.
舰长说
The captain says,
唯一的支援
the only support
是政府军可以安排直升机协助我们撤离
will be a chopper for evacuation,
但是没有具体时间
but they can't say when.
除了邓梅之外
In addition to Mei Deng,
我想把其他的人质全都救下来
I want to rescue the others too.
你有什么方案？
Do you have a strategy?
如果要救那么多人走的话
With so many people,
就不可能原路返回了
we can't take that road back.
不如干脆
It's better
直接带所有人穿过人质营北面的沙漠
to go north through the desert,
去政府军基地
straight to the army base.
但问题是
The problem is
目标太大 敌人一旦追上来的话…
we'll be exposed if they started to chase us.
邓梅还是首要任务
Mei Deng is the priority.
等邓梅安全撤离原路返回之后
Once she's safely out,
我们再集中火力去打人质营
we regroup and get the hostages.
你赶紧通知一下石头
Quickly tell Shitou
还有佟莉
and Li Tong
让他们化装成恐怖分子
to disguise themselves as terrorists
潜入人质营
and infiltrate the camp.
记住 是让佟莉和邓梅互换服装
Remember. Li Tong and Mei Deng will trade clothes.
让石头带着她原路返回
Shitou will take her back the way we came.
你还要去通知一下顾顺和李懂
Tell Shun Gu and Dong Li.
让他们寻找制高点
Find an over watch
控制住整个广场区域范围
where they can control the square.
一会儿我们进到镇里
Once we enter the town,
所有人的信号都会被屏蔽
all our signals will be jammed.
所以我现在要找到庄羽
So I have to tell Yu Zhuang
通知他加设反干扰器
to set up an anti-jamming device
确保我们所有人行动当中的通讯
to secure our communications.
至于夏楠
As for Nan Xia,
就让她跟庄羽留守在这儿吧
have her stay here with Yu Zhuang.
等邓梅撤出之后 他们一起撤离
They'll go as soon as Mei Deng's out.
最后 你 我 还有陆琛
Finally, you, Chen Lu and I
负责在广场范围内附近
will watch the square.
一旦说邓梅安全地通过这个地方
Once we know Mei Deng is safe and has arrived
撤到贝拉家
at Bella's house,
我们要第一时间
we'll blow up
把通往人质营的入口炸掉
their access to the camp.
然后我们三个人进入人质营
The three of us will go into the camp
带着全部的人质从这里撤出
and rescue the other hostages.
可是如果佟莉留在人质营
But if Li Tong is with them,
万一广场一旦打起来了
and a battle breaks out in the square,
咱们火力不够 人手不够
we won't have enough firepower.
你们现在已经人手不够
You're already outnumbered.
除非拿我去换
I'll switch with Mei Deng.
我比较更像一些
I look more like her too.
队长
Captain,
我觉得这个方案可行
I think that's not a bad idea.
我觉得这个方案不可行
I disagree.
我…什么也不知道
I know nothing.
没有话要告诉我？
Do you have nothing to say?
求求你…
Please.
我不知道你想知道什么？
What do you want to know?
你的伤口处理得不太好
Your wound is not looking so good.
- 我真的不知道… - 我要帮你重新处理
- I really don't know-- - Let me fix it.
求求你…我什么也不知道
Please, I know nothing!
你好像藏了点东西？在哪？
You're hiding something. Where is it?
我真的不知道…
I really don't know...
好好回想一下
Think it over.
阿路卡沙漠
Aluka Desert!
李懂
Dong Li,
这个范围你来负责
you cover this area.
顾顺
Shun Gu,
拱门后是你的
you take the arches.
没问题 我的
No problem. Got them.
队长 我们进入人质营
Captain, we're in.
按我说的做
Do as I say.
中国海军来救你了
The Chinese Navy is here to save you.
陆琛 我找到一辆货车
Chen Lu, I found a truck.
我会停在人质营的通道口
I'll stop it near the hostage camp.
你守在右侧
Guard the right flank.
我准备炸弹
I'll prepare the bomb.
零一零一
Base,
我是一队
this is Unit One.
是否收到？
Can you read me?
庄羽 庄羽 出什么问题了？
Yu Zhuang, what's wrong?
队长 与军舰联系中断了
Captain, we lost contact with the ship.
我马上检查
I'll go check.
收到 注意安全
Roger. Stay safe.
知道
Will do.
首领
Boss.
我们在后山山顶发现了中国军人
There's a Chinese soldier on the hill.
处决那个中国女人质
Execute the Chinese hostage.
这帮人要来救人
If they want to rescue her,
就让他们救个死人
let them rescue a corpse.
通知山上的兄弟
And tell our brothers
向中国军舰发动攻击
to attack the ship.
你们在干什么？
What are you doing?
队长 夏楠突然被带走了
Captain, they just took Nan Xia.
徐宏 怎么是夏楠？
Hong Xu, why was Nan Xia there?
石头 石头
Shfiou,
你们的车离开人质营之后
once you've left the camp,
你迅速下车 随时准备突袭人质营
jump out and prepare to attack it.
其他一切
Everyone else,
等邓梅安全通过广场之后再行动
hold fire until Mei Deng is safe.
你们在干什么？
What are you doing?
李懂 李懂
Dong Li,
我现在要进指挥所
I'm going into the headquarters.
找位置掩护我
Cover me.
李懂 我现在在二楼左边通道
I'm on the second floor, left passage.
看到我吗？
Can you see me?
看到
I see you.
帮我守着这里
Secure the area.
收到
Roget
那个女人太吵了
She's so loud.
把音乐调大声点
Turn up the music.
报告舰长 政委
Captain, Commissar.
山上恐怖分子车上的武器
Reporting, the weapons on the hill
已对准我们
are aiming at us!
全舰进入一级战斗部署
Battle-ready deployment grade one!
- 是 - 一级战斗部署 一级战斗部署
- Yes, sir! - Grade one!
副炮准备拦截
Auxiliary gun on intercept!
主炮瞄准山上目标
Main gun target the hill!
是
Yes, sir!
主炮锁定目标
Target is locked!
发射
Fire!
莫哈迪每分每秒都在残害我族人民
Mohadi is ruining our people's lives every day.
勇敢的战士不会能再等下去
And brave soldiers like us can wait no longer.
我们必须对这个中国人予以惩罚
We must punish this Chinese citizen.
只有鲜血才能让你们得到教训…
Only blood will teach--
等等
Wait!
你是谁？
Who are you?
原来那个女人在哪儿？
Where is the other girl?
你是怎样混进来的？
Who brought you here?
有多少同伙？
How many of you are here?
回答我
Answer me!
究竟有多少同伙？
How many of you are here?
再不说话 先把你的腿打断
Start talking or I'll break your legs!
快回答我
Answer me now!
你是活得不耐烦了吧
Do you want me to kill you?
对不起
I'm sorry.
这事换成别人 也得这样
Don't take it personally.
队长队长 现在离开人质营
Captain, we're leaving the camp.
走啊
Come on!
这就是威廉 项链不见了
This is William. His necklace is gone.
- 什么项链？- 资料全在里面
- What necklace? - It has the information.
走
Let's go.
队长 我现在准备进入广场
Captain, I'm about to enter the square.
但是车胎破了
But I got a flat tire.
所有人都稳住
Keep calm, everyone.
李懂 我现在准备出来
Dong Li, I'm coming out.
通道有没有问题？
ls the path clear?
没问题
All clear.
所有人注意
Everyone, listen to me.
不管我这边有什么情况
No matter what happens over here,
一切按原计划进行
stick to the plan.
轮胎漏气了
Your tire is flat!
待会儿不管发生什么
Remember.
记住 带着小女孩
No matter what happens, take the girl
跟紧我
and follow me.
别害怕 跟紧我 艾伊莎
Don't be scared, Aisha. Stay with me.
等等 轮胎漏气了
Wait, the tire is leaking air.
队长 佟莉的车被拦截了
Captain, they stopped Li Tang's truck.
有入侵者 有入侵者
Intruders!
我们要撤去旁边的废车场
We're retreating to the junkyard.
掩护我
Cover us!
跟紧我
Follow me.
走
Go!
进去
Go in!
躲起来
Hide!
找掩护
Find cover!
穿上它
Put this on!
徐宏 你们那儿情况怎么样？
Hong Xu, what's your status?
队长 我们在广场被困住了
Captain, we're trapped in the square.
你那边怎么样？
What about you?
只要有机会
When you have the chance,
带着所有人从后方人质营撤出
take them all out using the back way.
收到
Roget.
你怎么办？
What's your plan?
我在想办法
I'll think of one.
记住
Remember, make sure Mei Deng is safe!
一定要确保邓梅的安全
YELLOW CAKE '27 TONS
黄饼27吨 运输机于1625抵达藏匿地点坐标
你们继续攻 我会解决他们的狙击手
Keep on going. I'll take care of the snipers.
李懂 我被发现了
Dong Li, they saw me.
他离我位置很近
He's close by.
一定会死盯我
He know where I am.
我们要赶紧把他找出来
Find him quickly.
收到回复
Do you read me?
是
Roger
队长
Captain,
对方狙击手发现我了
their sniper found me.
我失去那个位置了
I've lost my position.
小心
Be careful.
起来
Get up!
往后面走 低头
We'll go that way! Heads down!
佟莉 佟莉
Li Tong!
你有没有事？
Are you okay?
回答我
Answer me!
车场入口被火封住了
Our exit is cut off by fire.
火烧过来了
It's coming our way!
陆琛
Chen Lu!
给我手榴弹
Give me a grenade!
给
Here!
佟莉
Li Tong!
来废车场后方
Get to the back.
待这儿别动
Stay right here.
徐宏 徐宏
Hong Xu!
佟莉
Li Tong,
从旁边炸出去
blast your way out.
我接应你
I'll cover you!
去
Go!
起来 走
Let's
陆琛 掩护佟莉
Chen Lu, cover Li Tong.
我们从后方撤入人质营
We'll retreat to the camp.
佟莉 撤
Li Tong,go!
跟着我
Follow me!
回去
Go back!
陆琛 退退退
Chen Lu, fall back!
我们要冲出去
We have to escape.
把这销子拔掉
Pull this pin.
我让你扔的时候就扔 听明白了吗？
When I say throw, you throw. Got it?
得跟他们干到底
We'll fight to the end!
走
Let's
夏楠 扔进去
Nan Xia, throw!
走
Move!
炸死他们 炸死他们
Blow them up!
听到没有？
Do you hear me?
马上解决全部人质
Kill the hostages!
他们要马上杀掉所有人质
They're going to kill the hostages!
石头 石头 马上行动
Shitou, go to the camp now!
打倒人质营 不要让他们杀了人质
Save the hostages! Don't let them kill the hostages!
副队
Sir,
人质营出口已打通
the exit is clear.
人质全部安全撤离
The hostages are all safe.
你们赶快过来
Hurry over here!
石头 通往人质营的路被炸了
Shitou, the exit's blocked!
快过来支援
Help us!
退后点 躲起来
Stay back, hide!
徐宏 我没子弹了
Hong Xu, I'm out of ammunition!
石头 支援陆琛
Shitou! Go and help Chen Lu!
再坚持一会儿
Hang in there.
我有办法
I have a plan.
明白
Roget
废车场右侧有出口通往小广场
There is a way out to the small plaza at right of the junkyard.
你们从那边出去
Use that way to get out.
我掩护你们突围
I'll cover you.
等我指示
Wait for my signal.
陆琛 佟莉
Chen Lu, Li Tong.
我抢了一辆坦克
I've taken over a tank.
我先解决你那儿的敌人
I'll deal with the enemies around you.
听我指示 注意隐蔽
Stay hidden and wait for my signal.
佟莉 佟莉
Li Tong.
记得冲出去之后
After you have escaped,
赶往集合点
go to the meeting point.
明白
Roger.
队长 下一炮救你出去
Captain, I'll rescue you next!
准备…
Ready.
开炮
Fire!
队长 队长
Captain,
你在什么位置？
what's your position?
我在主通道的右边
I'm at the right of the main passage.
但是被左边的恐怖分子困住了
But I'm surrounded by the terrorists on the left.
知道了
Got it.
准备
Ready!
隐蔽
Take cover!
开炮
Fire!
穿上
Wear this!
走 走
Move!
队长
Captain,
我们在小广场找到一辆车
we found a truck.
现在离开
We're moving now.
邓梅安全
Mei Deng is safe.
走啊
Go!
庄羽 庄羽 收到请回答
Yu Zhuang, do you read me?
收到
Yes.
你马上联系军舰
Contact base.
然后带着尤娜
Then take Yuna
到山上的集合点待命
to the meeting point and wait for orders.
听到了吗？
Do you read me?
收到
Roger.
零一零一
Base,
我是一队
this is Unit One.
零一零一 我是一队
Base, this is Unit One!
一队一队 收到回复 收到回复
Unit One, do you read me?
舰长 蛟龙的联络讯号消失了
Captain, we've lost Jiaolong's signal.
我们在尝试主动发送
We tried to reach them,
但一直没有回应
but to no avail.
他们的个人定位呢？
How about their individual positions?
也找不到他们个人讯号
We've lost those too.
保持一级戒备 继续联系
Stay on high alert, keep trying.
是
Yes, sir!
舰长
Captain.
现在我舰受到威胁
The ship is under threat.
为了侨民的安全
To protect the citizens on board,
我建议我们先退到外港
we'll move away from the port.
好
Okay.
我想向上级请示一下
Let me see if our superiors
同意我们派出无人机
will approve of sending in a drone.
跟着我
Follow me!
快 快来
Come on! Come on!
顾顺 顾顺
Shun Gu!
队长队长 收到请回话
Captain, do you read me?
蹲低
Get down!
趴下
石头
Shitou!
有没有信号
Any Signal yet?
没有
No.
先回集合点
To the meeting point.
走
Go.
石头 别动
Shitou, don't move!
别动
Don't move!
下车 下车
Out of the car!
快 快 快
Hurry!
蹲下 蹲下
Get down!
躲起来 躲起来
Take cover!
别动
Don't move!
石头 挺住
Shitou, hold on!
佟莉他们有危险
Li Tong and the others are in danger.
在下面
They are down there.
报告 发现微弱的蛟龙信号
Reporting. We have Jiaolong but the signal's weak.
但附近地区怀疑出现大规模沙尘暴
But there's a sandstorm nearby.
能联系上吗？
Did you make contact?
受天气影响 目前还没连线
Not yet for now due to weather interference.
还有多久到？
How much longer?
还有七分钟
We have seven minutes.
你们比我更需要
You need it more.
别出来
Stay there!
佟莉 佟莉 你们撑住
Li Tong, hang on!
我们马上就到
We're nearly there.
快
Hurry!
快点
陆琛 守住入口
Chen Lu, secure the entrance.
没事 石头…
It's okay, Shitou.
没事
It's okay.
好疼啊…
It hurts...
吃糖…
Have a candy.
吃糖不疼
The candy will help.
你不是说过…
Didn't you say
你说过吃糖不疼
that candy can kill the pain.
你说过吃糖不疼…
It takes away the pain.
吃糖…
Here. Eat this candy.
快
Come on.
吃糖不疼…
Candy takes away the pain...
我们回家了
We're going home.
回家了…
Going home...
石头
Shitou!
不疼了…我们回家了…
No more pain. We're going home...
坦克A 走右边攻击他们
Tank Alpha, attack from the right!
徐宏
Hong Xu.
往左20度 快 快
Turn 20 degrees left, hurry!
徐宏
Hong Xu.
他们的反应装甲太密集了
The reactive armor protects them.
往左急转
Turn a sharp left.
我们打他的履带
Shoot at their treads.
打中啦
Got them!
队长 冷却系统被打坏了
Captain, they hit our cooling system.
车开不了多久了
We won't last much longer.
队长
Captain,
前面有沙尘暴
there is a sandstorm ahead!
加速冲进去
Charge straight at it.
正好让风沙掩护我们
It will cover us.
徐宏 徐宏
Hong Xu.
我们的炮塔被打中了
Our turret took a hit.
不要让他们锁定
Don't let them lock onto us!
徐宏
Hong Xu.
我要用你的移动方向代替射击角度
I'll use your steering for aim.
明白吗？
Do you understand?
明白
Roger
夏楠
Nan Xia.
我们俩需要换一下位置
We have to switch places.
手柄上有一个按钮是发炮的
The handset has a trigger.
我让你发炮 你按下去
When I say fire, press it.
我去接应你
I'll help you.
徐宏
Hong Xu.
用我们的反应装甲接他一炮
Let the reactive armor take a hit.
待会儿你先往左急转
Follow my orders.
再往右转 你听我指示
First, take a sharp left and then sharp right!
徐宏 往左转
Hong Xu, turn left!
右转
Turn right!
夏楠 准备
Nan Xia, get ready!
开炮
Fire!
队长 队长
Captain!
车开不动了 车开不动了
We're stuck!
队长 我去解决他们的坦克
Captain, I'll deal with their tanks!
徐宏 徐宏
Hong Xu! Hong Xu!
夏楠 我们也出去
Nan Xia, we're going out.
记着
Remember.
出去之后把手搭在我肩膀上
When we go out, keep your hand on my shoulder.
听明白了吗？
Understand?
待在这儿别动
Wait here, don't move!
舰长 政委
Captain, Commissar.
无人机已经侦测到杨锐 徐宏的定位
The drone has found Rui Yang and Hong Xu.
但仍未取得联系
But we still don't have contact.
报告 无人机动力失控
Reporting, the drone is losing power
随时会坠落
and could drop at any time.
快 他要打我们了
They're attacking, quick!
快 马上装填
Load up, hurry!
准备发炮
Prepare to fire!
怎么样？
Are you okay?
还行…还行…
Yes, I am...
枪打得不错
You're a good shot.
队长
Captain.
任务完成了
Our mission is accomplished.
杨队长
Captain Yang.
感谢你们
Thank you so much.
- 杨队长 - 谢谢
- Captain Yang. - Thank you.
受天气影响
The weather is preventing us
我们暂时联系不到你们的军舰
from contacting your warship,
黄饼的事情我们现在暂无暇处理
and we are unable to deal with the "yellow cake" situation at the moment.
最多只能提供一架直升机
All we can provide is a helicopter.
这个…
This
非常管用
works pretty well.
记得还给我
Remember to give it back.
这次的黄饼危机
We can't just ignore
我们不可置之不理
this "yellow cake" crisis.
那些黄饼的藏匿地点
The hiding place for the "yellow cake"
距离此处80公里
is 80 kilometers from here.
但是还有40分钟
But in 40 minutes,
这些恐怖分子就会离开
the terrorists will leave with the "yellow cake".
所以我们必须抓紧时间
We have to hurry.
但是有一点我必须强调
But I need to stress one thing.
这次行动
This operation
还没有得到上级的批准
hasn't been authorized yet.
要扛
If we do this,
一起扛
we do it together.
队长
Captain.
我在等你下命令
I'll wait for your orders.
"强者无敌"
"Conquer fear, conquer all."
距离目标位置两公里
Two kilometers from destination!
我们的目标是抢黄饼
Our target is the "yellow cake".
所以不宜跟对方纠缠
Avoid engaging.
佟莉
Li Tong,
你跟我控制飞机抢黄饼
we'll take the plane and "yellow cake".
顾顺 李懂
Shun Gu, Dong Li.
找位置掩护我们
Find an over watch and cover us.
散开
Split up!
队长 我们到位
Captain, we're in position.
安全
Clear.
队长队长 指挥塔已控制
Captain, we've taken the control tower.
收到 原地待命
Roger. Wait for orders.
你先走 我等下一辆
You go first. I'll wait for the next truck.
首领
Boss.
叛军代表还有五分钟就到了
The rebels' representative will arrive in five minutes.
狙击点注意…
Attention, sniper's hide.
佟莉已经潜伏在卡车上出来了
Li Tong is under the truck.
看到她了
I see her.
刚才你提醒我那几枪打得不错
You did a good job just then.
我觉得这次回去
When we go back,
你可以加入主狙击手的训练
you can train as a sniper.
如果好的话
If I were that good,
我应该可以一枪做到的
I should have hit it at once.
就算再有经验 压力也还是会在的
Even the experienced feel pressure.
不要害怕它
Embrace it.
压力会让你更专注
Pressure keeps you focused.
没想到是你
I didn't know it'd be you.
好久不见了 首领
It's been a long time, boss!
你很久没有回家乡了
You've not been home in a long time.
打这一仗就是为了过更好的日子
We're fighting... for a better life.
还需要回乡？
Why go home?
这场仗不是为你们而打的
We're not fighting this war for you.
首领 资料呢？
What about the formula, boss?
全体注意 计划有变
Everyone, listen up. There is a change in our plan.
我现在要去抓他们首领
I'm going to go for their leader.
李懂 一会儿我出来的时候
Dong Li, when I come out,
一定会有追兵 你负责掩护我
they'll be after me. Cover me.
顾顺
Shun Gu,
你要负责协助佟莉解决飞机上的敌人
help Li Tong take the plane.
完毕
Over.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
叛军会吃掉我们
The rebels will eat us alive.
一定要把黄饼与资料带回来
You must bring back all the "yellow cakes".
干掉他们
Kill them all.
从现在起
From now on
这场战争是属于我们的
this war belongs to us.
明白了
I understand.
呼叫基地 求救 求救
Calling base! Mayday!
我们遇袭 支…
We're under attack! Help...
佟莉 佟莉 马上控制飞机
Li Tong, take control of the plane!
别动 别动
Don't move!
大家注意 我出来了
Everyone, I'm coming out.
李懂 留意
Dong Li, be careful!
李懂 你打最后一台
Dong Li, take out the last car!
顾顺 李懂
Shun Gu, Dong Li!
佟莉 收到回话
Li Tong, do you read me?
别动 别动
Don't move!
顾顺
Shun Gu!
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
下车
Get out!
快点
Hurry!
李懂
Dong Li,
用我的枪
use my gun.
放开首领
Let him go!
你没有时间考虑
There's no time to think!
快放人 不然我就杀死她
Let he go, or I'll kill her
李懂
Dong Li,
战胜压力
conquer the pressure.
罗星是不会选错人的
Xing Luo chose you for a reason.
队长
Captain,
佟莉那边的人我来解决
I'll take down the guy with Li Tong.
靠你了
I'm counting on you.
快放开他 不然我就杀了她
Do it now! I'll kill her!
妈的
Fuck!
他妈的中国人
Fucking Chinese!
这次的战争 我们不能没有这批黄饼
We need the "yellow cake" for this war!
为变得更强大而战
To become stronger!
"毒刺"防空导弹
队长
Captain,
叛军追来了
the rebels are behind us!
冷静
Calm down!
我是中国军人
I'm from the Chinese military.
启动引擎 快
Start the engine! Hurry up!
快 快
Hurry!
起步 走
March forward!
向右转
Turn right!
立定
Attention!
YU ZHUANG
TIAN-DE ZHANG
敬礼
Salute!
注意 我是中国海军
Attention! This is Chinese Navy.
你即将进入中国领海
You're about to enter Chinese waters.
请立即离开
Please turn around immediately!
注意 我是中国海军
Attention! This is Chinese Navy.
你即将进入中国领海
You're about to enter Chinese waters.
请立即离开
Please turn around immediately!
重复 请立即离开
I repeat! Please turn around immediately!